<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">turing_babbage</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="turing">Alan Turing</string>
    <string name="details_turing">Alan Mathison Turing,(23 June 1912 – 7 June 1954) was a British pioneering computer scientist, mathematician, logician, cryptanalyst, philosopher, mathematical biologist, and marathon and ultra distance runner. He was highly influential in the development of computer science, providing a formalisation of the concepts of \"algorithm\" and \"computation\" with the Turing machine, which can be considered a model of a general purpose computer. Turing is widely considered to be the father of theoretical computer science and artificial intelligence.\nDuring the Second World War, Turing worked for the Government Code and Cypher School (GC &amp; CS) at Bletchley Park, Britain\'s codebreaking centre. For a time he led Hut 8, the section responsible for German naval cryptanalysis. He devised a number of techniques for breaking German ciphers, including improvements to the pre-war Polish bomb method, an electromechanical machine that could find settings for the Enigma machine. Turing\'s pivotal role in cracking intercepted coded messages enabled the Allies to defeat the Nazis in many crucial engagements, including the Battle of the Atlantic, it has been estimated that the work at Bletchley Park shortened the war in Europe by as many as two to four years.\nAfter the war, he worked at the National Physical Laboratory, where he designed the ACE, among the first designs for a stored-program computer. In 1948 Turing joined Max Newman\'s Computing Laboratory at Manchester University, where he assisted development of the Manchester computers and became interested in mathematical biology. He wrote a paper on the chemical basis of morphogenesis, and predicted oscillating chemical reactions such as the Belousov–Zhabotinsky reaction, first observed in the 1960s.\nTuring was prosecuted in 1952 for homosexual acts, when such behaviour was still criminalised in the UK. He accepted treatment with oestrogen injections (chemical castration) as an alternative to prison. Turing died in 1954, 16 days before his 42nd birthday, from cyanide poisoning. An inquest determined his death a suicide; his mother and some others believed it was accidental. In 2009, following an Internet campaign, British Prime Minister Gordon Brown made an official public apology on behalf of the British government for \"the appalling way he was treated\". Queen Elizabeth II granted him a posthumous pardon in 2013.</string>
    <string name="babbage">Charles Babbage</string>
    <string name="details_babbage">Charles Babbage,(26 December 1791 – 18 October 1871) was an English polymath. A mathematician, philosopher, inventor and mechanical engineer, Babbage is best remembered for originating the concept of a programmable computer.\nConsidered a \"father of the computer\", Babbage is credited with inventing the first mechanical computer that eventually led to more complex designs. His varied work in other fields has led him to be described as \"pre-eminent\" among the many polymaths of his century.\nParts of Babbage\'s uncompleted mechanisms are on display in the London Science Museum. In 1991, a perfectly functioning difference engine was constructed from Babbage\'s original plans. Built to tolerances achievable in the 19th century, the success of the finished engine indicated that Babbage\'s machine would have worked.</string>

</resources>
